莱姆酒日记
飞吧*
Volare
唱吧*
Cantare
让我们飞入云端*
Let's fly way up to the clouds
远离攘攘尘凡*
Away from the maddening crowds
沐浴在星光下歌唱*
We can sing in the glow of a star that I know of
爱恋的人儿正缱绻*
Where lovers enjoy peace of mind
让我们忘却人间纷扰*
Let us leave the confusion
抛开俗世的羁绊*
And all disillusion behind
如比翼鸟儿一般*
Just like birds of a feather
共赏彩虹七色斑斓*
A rainbow together we'll find
飞啊*
Volare
唱啊*
E cantare
心儿为何在欢唱*
No wonder my happy heart sings
是爱赐予了我翅膀*
Your love has given me wings
波多黎各联碳公司欢迎您
-谁啊  -客房服务
- Who is it? - Room service.
鸡蛋吗
Is it eggs?
不知道  先生  不是我点的
I don't know, sir. I didn't order it.
要来些水吗
You want some water with that?
不  不用了
No, no. No, I don't.
看来您昨晚有的忙啊
Looks like you had a night.
好蛋
They look perfect.
出去吧
Get out.
本来我想找服务员来着
I intended to bring that to the attention of a member of staff.
这玩意儿弄不开
I had some difficulty getting it to open.
门钥匙里那把小的  先生
It's the little key on the door key, sir.
哦
Right.
我是想找点坚果
I was looking for some nuts.
原则上我不喝酒
I tend to avoid alcohol.
没酒的时候不喝
When I can.
我不会说西语
I don't speak Spanish.
四块五  没零钱
Cuatro cincuenta. No change.
不  不  你压根儿没听
No, no, no, no, you're not listening.
我是说海盗队  不是洋基队
I said the Pirates, not the Yankees.
我跟你说  今年罗伯特该火了
It's going to be Roberto's year, I'm telling you.
我找罗特曼先生
Looking for Mr. Lotterman.
里边那间
End of the room.
不  是海盗队
No, no, the Pirates.
你们这帮家伙全得完蛋
You guys are going to be all over.
那可是罗伯特・克莱门蒂啊  老兄
It's Roberto Clemente, man.
还有  我想说一下...
And by the way, I want to talk about...
主编  E・J・罗特曼
现在没空
Not now!
他现在是周五危机
He's having the Friday crisis.
-你是坎普  -对
- You Kemp? - Yeah.
他以为你昨天到
He was expecting you yesterday.
那边天气不好
We had some weather.
是  听说了
Yeah, I heard.
纽约下大雪
Big snow in New York.
他还打电话呢  来点咖啡吗
He's still on a call. You want some coffee?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
门口折腾什么呢
What's all the fuss out front?
你从前门进来吗
You came in the front?
我们不走前门
We don't use that door.
除非那帮乡巴佬消停下来
Not when los jibaros pitch up.
他们要干嘛
What do they want?
不知道
I don't know.
也就低保那些屁事
Some fucked idea of a living wage.
在那儿断断续续闹腾几个月了
They've been out there on and off for months.
对了  我叫萨拉
By the way, my name's Sala.
鲍勃・萨拉  摄影师
Bob Sala, staff photographer.
见到你很高兴  鲍勃
Pleased to meet you, Bob.
嗯
Yeah.
他打完了
He's off.
再试着轻轻敲敲门吧
You might want to try another subservient knock.
好
Yeah.
坎普
Kemp.
假装没看见他假发
Don't notice the wig.
干嘛  进
Yeah. What?
如果你是我想找的那个  坐下吧
If you're who I think you are, you better sit down.
你觉得屋里太亮吗
You find it a little bright in here?
我想摘了  可眼睛有点问题
I'd take them off, but I have a medical condition.
什么意思  你是个瞎子
What do you mean, you're blind?
结膜炎  先生
Conjunctivitis, sir.
就是红眼病吧
The old red eye, huh?
你过来得真是时候  坎普先生
You arrive at a very, very trying time, Mr. Kemp.
现在烂事一桩接一桩
One of those days stacking up.
所以  我们也不讲究什么了
So, uh, why don't we cut through the niceties
直入主题好吗
and just get right to it, huh?
我也希望如此
That's how I like to proceed.
好  这是你的简历
Okay. Your resume here.
很不简单
Very impressive CV.
没错
Yeah.
一些地方你包装得真不错
You worked your way up some interesting titles.
我很喜欢这个"西语流利"
I really like the "Fluent Spanish."
厉害啊
Wow.
你这简历...就是坨狗屎
This CV... This CV is a bunch of bullshit.
是吗
Is it?
这两天的电传稿
This is two days on the wire.
有一天的缺失
A day dead. We don't have it.
莫伯格搞得哪一出
What is the matter with Moburg?
他这跟死人有什么两样
He's about as useful as a dug-up body.
坎普先生  这报纸的问题就是
You see, the problem with this newspaper, Mr. Kemp,
连我都不愿意看
is that I am among many who don't enjoy reading it.
而且发行量低迷
We have an ailing circulation,
我一看周围这群废物
and I just have to look around this building
就明白为什么这样了
to understand why.
没有责任心  自负
Lack of commitment and too much self-indulgence.
所以我要寻找激情
So what I'm looking for
寻找活力
is some enthusiasm, some energy,
寻找新鲜血液
some fresh blood.
于是我想问你的第一个问题就是
And the question that I'm asking myself
你有多少酒量
is how much alcohol is usual in yours.
我血液里的吗
My fresh blood?
你能喝多少
How much do you drink?
我比能喝的人稍差点
I suppose at the upper end of "Social."
不过准备戒了
I'm poised to give up.
波多黎各可不是个
Well, Puerto Rico may not be
戒酒的好地方
the best place on Earth to do that.
别紧张  坎普先生
Don't look so anxious, Mr. Kemp.
我要是不雇你
I wouldn't have paid for
也不会掏钱让你住酒店
your hotel if I hadn't already hired you.
不过这不是废物聚集地
But this is not the Last Chance Saloon,
我也不想再雇个大酒鬼
and I do not need another heavy drinker.
从你墨镜后面的眼睛我就看得出来
Which I perceive, from the condition of eyeballs behind glasses,
你也是个酒鬼
that you might very well qualify as.
这是眼病  罗特曼先生
This is a medical condition, Mr. Lotterman.
我知道这看起来像别的原因  不过这
I know it might look like something else, but this is a...
看着就他妈像宿醉
Looks like a fuckin' hangover.
是吗
Does it?
过来
Come here.
这就是我想看到的献身精神
That's the kind of commitment I like to see in a man.
果敢  加之以适当的人性
Oh! Determination, balanced with appropriate humanity.
对  对  就这样
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
你是哪边的  坎普
Which side do you dress, Kemp?
什么
I beg your pardon?
政治倾向
Politics.
我算是中间派吧
I kind of hang in the middle.
这是个分裂的社会  坎普
This is a schizoid society, Kemp.
他们操两种语言  挂两样国旗
They got two languages, two flags
心怀不同的归属  唱不同的国歌
two loyalties, two anthems.
我们带来了他们前所未见的事物
We bring them stuff they never had.
他们要么恨之切切  要么欲罢不能
They either hate it or they want more of it.
这里不能算是美国的地盘
It's a reluctant part of America.
就像长了热带水果的英国吧
It's like an England with tropical fruit.
鲍勃
Bob.
这就是我要见那人
Just the man I wanted to see.
保罗・坎普  从纽约来加盟我们的
This is Paul Kemp. He's joining us from New York.
是  我们已经见过
Yeah, yeah, we already met.
那位是克里夫・多诺万先生  体育版的
Uh, that's... That's Mr. Clive Donovan, sports.
那位休伯特先生  会计
And this is Mr . Hubert, accounting.
帮我个忙好吗
Listen, do me a favor, will you?
带他转转  看看规章制度
Show him around, the dos and don'ts.
介绍下各位同事
Introduce him to some of the guys.
我带他去埃尔办公室
I'll take him up to Al's.
去那干吗
Oh, the hell you will.
领他去资料室
You take him to the library.
你调些合订本出来
You pull out some volumes.
先让他大致了解一下这份报纸
I want him to get a sense of the paper.
做点笔记  看看前几年的东西
You know, make some notes, go back a few years,
尤其是保龄球方面
paying particular attention to bowling alleys.
这边有保龄球
There's bowling and bowling alleys.
在这里很火  拓展得很快
Very big here. They're up like mushrooms.
每周都有新球馆开张
A new one premieres every week.
-来过波多黎各吗  -没有
- Been to Puerto Rico before? - No.
你会爱上这里的
Oh, you're going to fall right into it.
这里正值大发展  坎普  机会无限
There's a boom on here, Kemp. It's an open door.
只要好好把握  这就是你的天下
You play it right, you can surf the place.
你懂星座吗
What do you know about horoscopes?
不了解
Nothing.
要是我都能写  你也行
Ah, well, if I can write one, you can.
所以  每天一篇《明星星座》专栏
So it's every day with a special "Star's Star"
礼拜六来点贝蒂・格拉波和尼尔・塞达卡的八卦
featured Saturday with Betty Grable
这就差不多了
and Neil Sedaka, things like that.
好吧  你需要的一切都在这了
So here, everything you need is right there.
这称作《拉松加夫人预言》
It's called "Madam La Zonga Predicts."
拉松加夫人怎么了
What happened to Madam La Zonga?
废掉了
He got canceled.
什么意思  解雇了吗
What do you mean, fired?
被强暴致死
They raped him to death.
强暴致死
They raped him to death?
这岛上没几个地方
There are very few places on this island
我不愿意去
I decline to visit,
不过坎达度码头西侧
but the toilets frequented by sailors
水手出没的厕所就是其一
on the west side of Candado Pier is one.
他被强暴致死
They raped him to death?
拉松加死在一个厕所隔间
La Zonga died in a cubicle.
那个  你不是搞艺术的吧  坎普
Say, you're not, uh, artistic, are you, Kemp?
不是
Oh, no.
那最好就不要抽薄荷烟了
You might want to rethink those menthol cigarettes.
一点好处没有
They don't do a thing for you.
有空去逛
Come by the house.
好的
I will.
我喜欢你的东西
I like your stuff.
发给罗特曼的剪报
The cuttings you sent to Lotterman.
写得真不错
Oh. It's good writing.
谢谢
Thanks.
回头聊
We'll talk.
再加一层
One more floor!
半年前他们装上了自动打包机
They put in automated packing machines about six months ago.
几乎全部机械化了
They mechanized almost everything.
过去下面用五十号人  现在只要五个
There used to be 50 guys down here. Now there's five.
所以才有现在的"街头狂欢"
Hence happiness in the street.
入职留念
Souvenir, day one.
为想入非非的美人们干杯
Here's to pretty women with filthy thoughts.
-要汉堡吗  -不用
- Want a burger? - No.
-汉堡  -不  谢谢
- Burger? - No, thanks.
尝尝看  两个
Try it. Dos.
入职过程怎么样
So how was the induction?
有点担心
Somewhat fraught.
恕我直言  保罗  他真是没的挑了
No disrespect, Paul, but he didn't have a lot of choice.
你知道有多少人应聘这个职位吗
You know how many people applied for the job?
就你一个
One. You.
真的啊
Is that right?
即便如此  我还是觉得没表现好
Even then, I thought I'd blown it.
话题尽围绕着我的劣势
Zeroed in on my weakest spot.
什么劣势
Which is what?
两部半没出版的小说
Two and a half unpublished novels
还有一样扯淡的推荐信
and references of equal fiction.
你是小说家啊
Oh, you're a novelist.
说起来也算
Mmm, in a manner of speaking.
可就是没人读过
Can't even get read.
所以我想还是码点字赚几个钱
So I figured I'd do some words for money,
过一两年再看
see how it's looking in a year or two.
在《星报》啊
At El Star?
你刚来真不忍告诉你
Hate to tell you this on the way in,
可这张报纸正走下坡路
but this publication's on its way out.
就我来看  马上就要撑不下去了
And as far as I'm concerned, it can't come soon enough.
不会吧
Not going to happen.
要打赌吗
You like a little vonga on that?
我跟你赌报纸六月份停办  6.5的赔率
I'll give you 13 to 2 this thing's over by June.
他们都要掐掉电传了
They're going to cut the cord.
那干嘛还更换新设备
Then why put in all the new machinery?
说的是啊  看他怎么解释
Precisely my point, and he can't answer it.
我真懒得争  明摆着的
Well, like I'm tired of arguing the obvious.
走吧  吃点东西
Come on. Let's eat.
我要去找个人  谈马匹的事
Now, I got to go and see a man about a horse.
很高兴认识你  保罗
Good to meet you, Paul.
古老的圣胡安又迎来了新的一夜
Another night unfolds over Old San Juan.
你来很久了吗
You been here long?
太久了
Too long.
这地方就像你已经上过的姑娘
This place is like someone you fucked
却还赖在你的身下
and they're still under you.
干嘛不辞职呢
Why don't you quit?
退路无处不在
Life's full of exits.
因为我要等报社垮掉  领取遣散费
Because I'm waiting for it to collapse so I get the payoff.
三千块足够我扎进墨西哥了
Three grand redundancy puts me in Mexico.
别向左看
Don't look left.
你肯定不想认识他
That's an introduction you don't want to have.
他是谁
Who's he?
报社所有问题的缩影
Living example of everything that's wrong with this paper.
他叫莫伯格
His name's Moburg.
罪案与宗教事务部记者
Our Crime and Religious Affairs correspondent.
罗特曼见不到他人  想炒他都炒不掉
Lotterman can't fire him because he never sees him.
白天他基本不出门
He's rarely out in daylight.
看他很爱喝酒啊
Looks like he enjoys a drink.
他现在脑子里只有朗姆酒了
The entire substructure of his brain is eaten away with rum.
跟你说吧  这报社完了
I'm telling you, this enterprise is doomed.
楼里可能就三四个职员
There's maybe three or four
苦苦支撑着
professionals in the building running the entire show.
等一下  谁是豪尔・桑德森
Wait a minute. Who is Hal Sanderson?
在资料室  他是谁
In the library. Who's he?
过去他在报社
He used to work for the paper.
现在他自封为公关顾问
Now he's what he says he is a PR consultant.
向美国佬四处推销地皮
Selling this place street by street to the Yankees.
一个叫赛古拉的滑头是他的联系人
Keeps a greasy little bastard of a contact called Segurra.
我见过他  没打招呼
I saw him. We didn't meet.
没关系
Wouldn't bother.
理都不要理他
Piss on the make.
赛古拉那小子秉性不善
The boy, Segurra, is at the property wickedness.
我不知道桑德森适合干哪行
I'm not sure where Sanderson fits.
不过桑德森值得培养
But Sanderson's worth cultivation.
他有不错的人脉
He's got some good connections.
对自由记者有些帮助
He's good for some freelance.
今晚我被这里弄得太郁闷了
This place is depressing me beyond belief tonight.
你是住仙都酒店吧
You're at Plage Xanadu, right?
来吧  我送你回去
Come on. I'll give you a ride.
我在想  要是你想找住处
I was thinking, if you need somewhere,
我有间房可以租给你
I got a room for rent.
地段不算好  不过有冰箱和电视
Not the best address in town, but it's got a fridge and TV.
每月六十
60 a month.
听着不错  我考虑一下
Sounds inviting. I might remention that.
现在花老板的钱别心疼
Meanwhile, bleed it dry.
先生
Uh, sir...
我想游泳
I was hoping for a swim.
泳池今晚关闭
The pool is closed tonight.
是吗  为什么  怎么了
Really? Why? What's going on?
联碳公司有个派对
It's a Union Carbide party.
私人晚会
It's a private function.
不好意思
Sorry.
我没注意到船上有人
I didn't realize anyone was there.
还以为是漂过来的
I thought it was just floating.
就是漂过来的
It is just floating.
你和我一样吗
You doing what I'm doing?
不一样吧
I don't think so.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
离开乏味的派对
Escaping the dreadful party.
悄悄溜出来裸泳
I just snuck out and unzipped.
你可真勇敢
Well, that's very courageous of you.
我还当你是条美人鱼呢
I thought maybe you were a mermaid.
人们说海边有很多美人鱼
They tell me the coast is infested with them.
我来自康涅狄格州
I'm from Connecticut.
我男朋友正在演讲
My boyfriend's making a speech.
正好二十一分钟的演讲
Takes exactly 21 minutes.
现在说请你喝杯酒
Well, then I guess it's pointless,
是不是没意义
me inviting you for a drink.
你有什么酒
What you got?
这里没有  我是说去酒吧
No, I mean at the bar.
是没意义
Pointless.
我还是趁他们找我之前回去
I'd better go before they wonder where I went.
等等  你叫什么
Wait a minute. What's your name?
当成个秘密吧
Let's keep that a secret.
我还不知道呢
I don't even know it.
那就更秘密了
Well, then you'll keep it even better.
你什么星座
What about your star sign?
我是个资深天文学家
I'm an experienced astronomer.
没准是双鱼吧
Could try Pisces.
鱼
The fish.
天呐
Oh, God.
为什么她就出现了
Why did she have to happen?
明明还是心如止水  偏偏却冒出个她
Just when I was doing so good without her.
二位最喜欢波多黎各什么
What would you say you like most about Puerto Rico?
保龄球馆和赌场
The bowling alleys and the casinos.
当然  她喜欢的是免税
Course, she likes the duty free.
你花的越多  省的就越多
Well, the more you spend, the more you save.
在岛上四处观光了吗
Have you seen a lot of the island?
我们就没离开酒店
We don't leave the hotel.
不安全啊
It isn't safe.
可玩得很开心吧
But you're having fun?
是啊  非常开心  太爽了
Oh, yeah! A lotta, lotta fun!
跟他妈傻胖子寻开心
Have some fun with a fucking Luger.
球馆很能吸引这帮吃货
These alleys are magnets to the glutton.
他们犹如过江之鲫
They come off the boats like locusts.
一帮肥硕的猪头
Beasts of obesity.
屁股中箭都感觉不到
Asses that wouldn't feel an arrow.
伟大的白种人
The great whites.
也许就是地球上最危险的物种
Probably the most dangerous creatures on Earth.
你的明星来了
There's your baby.
沃尔特和他妻子
Walt and his woman.
保龄球馆并不是我想的那样
Bowling alleys isn't exactly what I had in mind.
等冬天过了再看看吧
Tread it till the snow melts,
跟着大批的游客散去
then join the exodus.
在冲片子
Red light!
找坎普
Looking for Kemp.
形容词过多  过于尖酸刻薄
Too many adjectives, too much cynicism.
没人想知道这里的问题
Nobody wants what's wrong with the place,
人们要看这里好的一面
they want to read about what's right.
-这是二稿  -知道  我看出来了
- It's a rewrite. - Yeah, I'm aware of that.
等你改的时候
And while you're at it,
最好重新拟一个标题  叫
you might want to rewrite the title and call it
《波多黎各之十大最爱》
"Ten Things That I Love About Puerto Rico."
那么
So,
酒戒得怎么样了
how's the sobriety coming along?
正在减量
I'm cutting down.
你的意思是  你不喝大瓶改喝小瓶了吧
Oh. By that, I assume you mean the size of the bottles.
你怎么喝的161瓶朗姆酒
How does anybody drink 161 miniatures?
你平均一个星期喝93瓶啊
You're averaging 93 miniatures a week.
酒店是不是一天得给你补充四次
What, do they stock the place four times a day?
朗姆酒供应不是免费的吗
Are they not complimentary?
是的  坎普先生  不是免费的
No, Mr. Kemp, they are not.
葡萄酒和长途电话同样也不是
And neither is wine and long-distance phone calls.
到下周一  你就给我搬出仙都
So, as of Monday, you are no longer a resident of the Xanadu.
什么风把你给吹来了
And what exactly brings you into the building?
别烦我
Don't hazel me.
我拿到X光片了  我活不过一个星期了
I got the X-rays back. I got less than a week to live.
烦你  你在胡说什么  你个瑞典佬
Hazel you? What are you talking about, you Swedish twerp?
你那快烂光的脑子里想过没
You know, it may have crossed what's left of your mind
我这里是办报纸的
that I have a newspaper to run here,
外面那些事叫新闻
that we have something called news going on out there.
但是与其等着你报道新闻
But as far as you're concerned,
我还不如自己亲自看
I might as well look out of the fuckin' window!
你来这儿干吗
What are you doing here?
这里是报社
This is a newspaper.
没你需要的东西
There's nothing here for you.
你以前两条最棒的独家新闻
Two of the best scoops you ever had
都是我想出来的
came out of my brain.
你说话最好注意点
And you better moderate your language
不然我可去别处了
or I'll go elsewhere.
别处  哪里的别处
Elsewhere where?
苍蝇你都拍不死
You couldn't get work as a fly repellent.
你简直一无是处  莫伯格
You're worthless, Moburg.
毫无利用价值
The last onion in the jar.
别逼我  罗特曼
Don't push me, Lotterman.
狗急了也会跳墙的
I'm dangerous when pushed.
我知道你为什么来了
Oh, I know why you're here.
今天发工资嘛
It's payday.
但是你
But in your case,
再也领不到工资了
deferred on a permanent basis.
你已经被解雇了
You're fired!
你不能解雇我
You can't fire me.
你还欠我工资呢
You owe me money.
你最好发给我  不然把我惹急了
And you better pay it, or I'll come through the roof
我把你这变成保险公司
and turn this place into an insurance claim.
你是在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
大家都冷静点吧
Hey, guys, let's take it easy.
你想体验一下被巫毒诅咒的滋味吗
You want to suffer some voodoo?
你个疯子
You twerp!
吃招吧  罗特曼
Eat the death pill, Lotterman!
走  咱不跟他计较
Come on, we're walking.
你听见他对我说什么了吗
Did you hear what he said to me?
我这高血压就是拜他所赐
This guy's my blood pressure.
早晚我要死在他手下
This guy's going to kill me.
那张照片的底片必须给我毁掉
And I want the negative of that picture destroyed!
别让那蠢货再进来
I don't want that animal in this building again.
看着就恶心
He is hygienically unacceptable.
你看见他鼻子那儿了吗
Did you see the side of his nose?
密密麻麻的黑头跟盲文似的
Blackheads like Braille.
他们应该直接抓他
They should have him put down.
莫伯格绝对是个人物
Moburg is history.
我们一招到人他马上滚蛋
He's out of here at the earliest opportunity.
而这个人
And the earliest opportunity
就是你
is you.
你明白我在说什么吗  坎普
You understand what I'm saying, Kemp?
我想我明白
I think I get the drift.
我希望你能全身心地投入到我们的报纸中
I want you to immerse yourself into this paper,
因为你有才华  我觉得你也有这份心
'cause you got the talent and I think you got the will.
你可以随报社一起发展
You make it grow and you grow right along with it.
我恐怕做不了
I'm not best placed to do that.
你觉得我招你来就是让你负责星座
You think it's my intention to keep you on
和保龄球板块  每天润色润色新闻吗
horoscopes and rewrites and bowling alleys?
其实  我马上就给你任务
Matter of fact, I'm gonna move you right now.
打的去机场
Take a cab to the airport.
迈阿密的市长就要来访问了
The mayor of Miami's coming in.
让他说点好听的
Make him sound nice.
我要你给他拍照  采访他
I want a picture and an interview.
只准成功不许失败  保罗
Make it work, Paul.
你已经不在我的酒店住了吗
You leaving us already?
如果这位市长真能出现的话
I'm moving into an apartment
我就可以去住公寓了
if this mayor guy ever shows up.
机场公告牌上显示的一直是  航班延误
They keep changing "Delayed" To "Delayed."
想去吃点早餐吗
You want to have some breakfast?
在沙滩上来点小龙虾
Little lobster on the beach?
就20分钟的路
Twenty minutes away.
听起来不错  不过我得在这里等市长
Sounds inviting, but I got to wait for the mayor.
不会来啦
Isn't coming.
航班取消
Canceled.
公告牌上可不是这么写的
That's not what it says on the board.
马上就改
It will in a minute.
我刚刚给迈阿密打过电话
I just called Miami.
走吧  吃点儿早餐
Come on, let's have some breakfast.
我那有些你感兴趣的东西
I got a couple of things that might interest you.
我得打电话汇报一下
I better call in.
车上打
You can call from the car.
好的  知道了  谢谢
All right. Yeah, thanks.
在波多黎各只有两个这样的地方
There's only two of those on the island.
顶多三个
Maybe three.
没人告诉我这里这么美
No one told me it was so pretty here.
上帝赐予的财富
God's idea of money.
你知道这里因为什么叫金矿吗
You know what makes this place a gold mine?
因为有别处稀缺的东西
Something that doesn't exist.
此话怎讲
How's that?
土地
Land.
因为土地稀缺
There isn't enough of it.
拥有土地就意味着掘到了金子
Those who know how to get it get the gold.
香诺
Chenault?
保罗跟咱们一起吃早饭
Paul's joining us for breakfast.
差不多都成午饭了
Looks like it's gonna be a lunch.
这是香诺
This is Chenault.
你们俩以前认识吗
You two know each other?
不知道  可能在飞机上见过吧
I don't know, I thought maybe we met on the plane.
应该不会吧
Oh, I don't think so.
我坐的可是男朋友号专机
I flew Boyfriend Airlines.
你喜欢龙虾吗  保罗
Tell me, do you like lobster, Paul?
那个  今天可能不行了
You know what, I might not have time today.
我不知道开车来得这么长时间
I didn't realize the drive was gonna take so long.
你还有多长时间
How much time you got?
还有15分钟  再晚就迟到了
In 15 minutes, I'm late.
我去切个菠萝
I'll cut up a pineapple.
你还是穿上点衣服吧
You might want to put on some clothes.
她习惯脱了衣服晒日光浴
She sunbathes in the nude.
当地这些人把看她
A few of the over-tanned locals
当成是吸引游客的卖点
tend to treat it as a tourist attraction.
谁说不是呢
Doesn't surprise me.
我是说  这样的确很有品味
I mean that in a... In a very tasteful way.
这里是私人海滩
It's a private beach.
外人不应该来
They shouldn't be here.
坐吧  保罗  待会儿给你叫辆计程车
Sit down, Paul, sit down. We'll grab you a cab.
它叫哈利
His name's Harry.
一本书给的灵感
Got the idea from a book.
保罗  我想跟你谈谈
Paul, I wanted to talk,
因为我在找一个能
because I'm looking for someone who can
整合对立的观点
assimilate contradictory points of view
让大家统一口径的人
and make them into one voice.
你是个小说家  是吧
You're a novelist, right?
你听谁说的
Who told you that?
得了吧  报纸不就是写八卦的吗
Oh, please. Newspapers are full of gossip.
我刚想找一个擅长文字的人
I'm looking for someone
你马上就出现了
who's good with words, next day, you turn up.
我相信运气
And 'cause I believe in good luck,
没准你就是好运气
I thought maybe you were it.
我需要的
What I need
是一双敏锐的眼睛
is someone with the right kind of eyes.
用来观察什么
For looking at what?
观察这个
Looking at that.
金钱的海洋
An ocean of money.
你来啦
Hey, you made it.
走廊尽头那间
Door at the end.
再等我两分钟
Hey. Just give me two minutes.
进去吧
Walk right in.
好
All right.
我本来想在你来之前把这里收拾收拾的
I was trying to get the place shipshape before you arrived.
阿道夫・希特勒演讲集
Adolf Hitler Speaks?
不是我的  纳粹那些东西都是莫伯格的
Not mine. Nazi stuff belongs to Moburg.
莫伯格也在这里住吗
Moburg lives here?
他把工装放在这里
He keeps his uniform here.
不过我整月的见不到他
I never see him from one month's end to the next.
瞧瞧  这里还是很宽敞的
So, you can see, it's quite spacious.
厨房就别看了
Don't look in the kitchen.
停水了  水阀坏了
The water's off. There's a problem with the valve.
我记得你说你有个电视
Thought you said you had a TV.
我是说我有电视看
I said I kind of have a TV.
巷子对面的人有电视  我有望远镜
The guy across the alley has a TV, I have binoculars.
他老婆是个聋子
His wife's deaf.
要是开着窗户  什么都听得清
With the window open, you hear every word.
来了
Oh, here it comes.
来水了
Water's coming up.
我看见卧室里有几只鸡
I, uh, noticed you had some chickens in the bedroom.
是小公鸡
Cockerels.
瞧我热得我都冒油了
Yeah, I'm sweating the grease out.
别担心  我把它们弄到我屋里
Don't worry about them, I'm moving them to my room.
你要这些鸡做什么
What do you do with them?
-养了吃吗  -吃
- You eat them? - Eat them?
不  我才不吃呢
Nah. I don't eat them.
加油  宝贝  加油啊
Come on, baby, come on!
干它  干它
Get in there, get in there!
快
Come on!
乘胜追击啊  宝贝  乘胜追击
Hey, on a trade wind, my boy! On a trade wind!
来啊  加注啊  这才对嘛  鲍比
Come on, bump it up, there, Bobby.
加注  加注  太明智了  先生
Bump, bump, bump, bump. Yes, sir!
他们管这只鸡叫怪兽
Hey. They call him El Monstruo.
三年了从没输过
Say he's never lost a fight in three years.
走  咱走吧
Come on, we're out of here.
来  快点  跟上
Come on, rapido, rapido.
过去  快
Come on. Come on. Go on.
那只鸡出现以前  我的鸡一直所向披靡
I tell you, we were on a roll til that thing turned up.
一共是217美元
That's $217.
不赖
Not bad.
217美元算是一大笔钱了
$217 is a shitload of money.
相对而言不算多
Relatively a shitload.
训练这些鸡也很费钱的
They're expensive to train.
我见过有些人在北海滩赢两千甚至一万的
I've seen guys win 2,000, ten on North Beach.
一万
10,000?
那人为什么不去那里比赛
Why didn't he take El Monstruo down there?
北海滩那边是上流社会
You're talking the environs of the Hilton Hotel.
人都戴领结  穿锃亮的皮鞋
They wear bowties and shiny shoes.
他那种人是去不了的
There's no hope for his kind of hat.
总统竞选电视辩论  尼克松VS肯尼迪
所以说  问题不在于目标
The question, again, is not one of goals.
我们有目标
We're for those goals.
问题在于方法
It's one of means.
你是说艾森豪威尔政府
Were you claiming that the Eisenhower administration...
这场闹剧什么时候才能结束
How long can this blizzard of shame go on?
看看这个忘恩负义的人  还义正辞严的
Look at this ingrate besotted with his own righteousness.
黑肤色不过是深色的白皮肤
Black is a very dark shade of white.
谢谢您的回答  尼克松先生
Well, thank you very much, Mr. Nixon.
我听不下去了
I can't listen to any more of this.
他一句话八个谎
Lies like he breathes.
真难想象撒一辈子谎是什么样
Imagine spending your entire life lying.
上帝
Holy Christ.
没有比这更糟的
Never got worse.
比他更糟糕的只有  有一天
The only eventuality worse than him is you know that one day,
某个臭婊子出现
some filthy whore-beast is gonna show up,
把他变成个民主派
make him look like a liberal.
尼克松唯一的优点是他肯定赢不了
The only upside with Nixon is he ain't gonna win.
他有微笑他自豪
He's got the grin.
他赢不了
He ain't gonna win.
肯尼迪  爱尔兰移民后裔
爱尔兰人会赢
Irish guy's going to win.
不过他也活不长久
But they'll never let him live.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
我研究死亡运势
I do "Horror-scopes."
不是说他从不来吗
Thought you said he never came here.
他弄到过滤器了
He's got filters.
什么过滤器
What filters?
他翻墙摸进巴卡第的酿酒厂
He goes over the wall at the Barcardi plant.
过滤是蒸馏的最后一道工序
These filters are the last in line in the distillation process.
机器里边的酒精含量比火箭燃料里面的还多
They contain more ethanol than rocket fuel.
什么感觉
What's it like?
飘飘欲仙
A hand on the brain.
远离尘世
Off the scale.
470度
470 proof.
哪有470度的酒
No such thing as 470 proof alcohol.
你可不能说得这么绝对
Certainty you might be required to moderate.
此处禁止吸烟
No smoking in the extraction area, if you please.
开玩笑
Don't be ridiculous.
对酒鬼来说就是不行
Not for the social drinker.
想爽几口吗
You want to quaff?
不了
No.
现在不行  我有东西要写
Not right now. I got to write.
马上就得交稿
I got a deadline.
他在写什么
Oh, what's he writing?
他在质疑美国梦
He's lifting the stone on the American Dream.
瓜雅尼拉海湾[波多黎各海湾]
Guayanilla Bay.
是啊  那里正乱着呢
Oh, yeah. It's bad down there.
这样的话题没几个人感兴趣
You might find such a topic attracts a limited readership.
有人看就行
Only need one.
罗特曼看就够了
Taking it to Lotterman.
是啊  刚没人祝你好运吧
Yeah. Oh, did I hear somebody say "Good luck"?
我今早去了
Yeah, I went down there this morning,
他想这么解雇我  蠢货一个
he unfired me on a temporary basis, maggot that he is.
我想给罗特曼看样东西
I'd like to bring something in to Lotterman.
一把"干死你"霰弹枪
Like a slide-action, "Fuck you" Gun.
别在这里喝
Don't drink that here.
我就尝一口  老伙计
Just a nipperoo, old boy.
质量检测
Quality test.
慢动作枪杀  就跟电影里似的
Man, slow-motion murder, just like they do in the movies.
看他被崩出去
See him flying back,
伸着胳膊乱扑腾
fuckin' arms flapping in the air.
好吧  混账东西
Okay, mother.
盯着临死之前见到的这最后一张脸
Look upon the last face you'll see this side of hell!
砰
Bam!
他倒下了  血肉横飞
Down he goes, morsels of vital organs
七窍流血
spinning off into flesh orbit.
砰
Bam!
把他的屁眼嘣了
There goes his asshole.
砰
Bam!
老二也没了
There goes his dick.
砰砰
Bam! Bam!
去死吧  罗特曼
Fuck you, Lotterman!
这是部B级片  而我就是杀人机器
You're in a B-fucking movie, and I am the death machine!
咱听希特勒的演讲吧
Shall we have some Adolf?
别了
Definitely not.
你赶紧忙你的去吧  莫伯格
On your way, on your way, Moburg.
我们这有客人要来
Hey, we're expecting guests.
我记得你说他在写书
I thought you said he was writing a book.
是说我在写文章
Said I was writing an essay.
需要安静的环境
And it requires some shut mouth.
别把你的时间浪费在那些蠢货身上
Oh, don't waste your time on those junkyard losers.
这个国家建立在种族灭绝和奴隶制之上
This country was built on genocide and slavery.
先杀死当地所有的黑人
We killed all the black guys that were here,
再运过来我们国家的黑人
and then we shipped in new black guys of our own,
然后跟带一块肥皂似的  把基督教带过来
and then we brought in Jesus, like a bar of soap.
我们走
Let's go.
你心知肚明
You know it.
我是宗教方面的记者
I am the religious correspondent.
让你们那一套耶稣的理论滚蛋吧
Fuck off with your Jesus Police!
如果圣经是上帝写的
If the Bible's God's book,
他为什么不每人发一本呢
why didn't He give it to everyone?
我们在停车收费器上的投入
"We give more money to parking meters
多于我们在孩子饮食上的投入
than we do to kids to eat."
别那种眼神  我是做了调查的
Don't read me like that. I've done the research.
1.2万吨的盐酸
12,000-ton rust bucket went down in the bay
一桶桶地全倒进了海湾
full of hydrochloric acid.
海洋里的生物集体毙命
Killed off everything in the sea.
渔夫也死了  剩下孩子们以捡破烂为生
Killed off the fishermen. Their kids are picking garbage.
好吧  别生气
All right, don't get angry.
这件事的确很受关注
It's hot outside.
来杯威士忌
You want a Scotch?
好
Yeah.
十年前  不  五年前
Ten years ago... Five. Five years ago,
我可能会告诉你继续关注
I might have said go after it.
现在我劝你视而不见
Now I say go with it.
你无能为力
There's nothing you can change.
有时你呕吐完了也只能接着划船
Sometimes you just got to spew over the side and keep rowing.
朝着坚果色的落日继续前进
Into a nut brown sunset.
这是片充斥着愤怒的土地
It's the land of multiple outrage.
你醒来吃早饭的时候
Thousands trodden on
早有成千上万的人受到了践踏
before you wake up for breakfast.
那不算是新闻  不过是商业现实
That isn't news, it's a commercial reality.
而且这落日早就不是他们的了
And providing it isn't their sunset,
谁他妈在乎呢
nobody gives one-fifth of a fuck.
你低估你的读者了
You underestimate your readers.
我不这样认为
I don't think so.
你低估我了
You underestimate me.
你让我好好干  而这就是我想做的
You told me to make it work, that's what I want to do.
停止星座那套废话  办真正的报纸
Wind down this La Zonga crap and make a newspaper.
让我告诉你一些不中听的真理
Let me tell you some home truth.
从这份报纸诞生之日起
This paper's been on its knees to a bank
它就对东家银行言听计从
since the day it opened.
跟地球上所有报纸一样
And like most every other newspaper on Earth,
经费来源是广告收入
it's financed by its advertising.
没有广告的话  不仅没有星座
And without advertising, not only is there no La Zonga,
连纸张都不会有  因此
there's no paper to put it in, so, thus,
有那么一两种事情我们是不会报道的
there are one or two things that we don't write about.
换句话说就是什么都不报道
In other words, nothing at all.
再换句话  这叫谨慎
In one other word, discretion.
你不是驻外记者
You're not a foreign correspondent
派驻在遥远的异国他乡  这里是美国
in some far-flung foreign land, this is America.
这里是波多黎各
This is Puerto Rico.
是美国
This is America.
你以为一个伊利诺伊诺莫尔市的水暖工
You think some plumber from Normal, Illinois,
用辛苦攒了25年的积蓄来这里度假
saves up for 25 years to come here on a cruise ship
是为了看糖料种植园如何陷入困境吗
to read about bad times in the sugar plantation?
他们才不管呢
They don't give a fuck!
一般人不会摇晃船身
The average guy don't rock the boat,
因为他想爬上船来
'cause he wants to climb aboard it.
而我们的读者就是这些一般人
And our readership is vividly average.
他们不关心谁是失败者
They don't care who the losers are.
他们只在意胜利者
They want to know who won.
谁赢了球赛
Who won the bowls,
谁赢了赛马  谁玩老虎机赚了
who won the races, who won the pot at the slot machines.
看着我  坎普
Look at me, Kemp.
你不是在睡觉  你清醒得很
You're not sleeping, you're wide awake.
而这就是美国梦
And this is the American Dream.
这么多酒店  你都看不见海了
So many hotels, you can't see the sea.
只有住进酒店才能看见海景
You can see the sea by checking into the hotels.
看海还得掏钱
Pay to see the sea?
这怎么了
What's the matter with that?
想呆在美国梦里  你就得付钱
You're paying to be in the dream.
在梦境与现实之间  坎普
There's a thin veneer, Kemp,
有一层薄板
between the dream and the reality.
你要是把梦里的人弄醒了
You wake them up and the
他们就要你退款
people might start asking for their money back.
听你的
You're the boss.
不尽然
Not quite.
这份报纸的社论立场由美国梦主导
The editorial policy of this newspaper is owned by the dream.
天哪
Oh, God.
上帝
Oh, Christ.
瞧啊
Oh, God, look at that.
天哪
Oh, God!
-豪尔  -啊?
- Hal? - Oh.
不不  我是豪尔的朋友
No, no, I'm a friend of Hal's.
我在欣赏他的游艇
I was looking at his boat.
真是艘好船
She's a sweet little beauty.
你坐过吗
You been aboard?
没
No.
极好的小岛旅行工具
Great little island hopper.
我们都坐过
We've all been down on her.
非常棒的经历
It's a wonderful experience.
你们俩来得真早
You two are early.
收获颇丰啊
Oh, you got lucky.
是啊
Yeah.
相互介绍过了吗
Did you meet?
是的  介绍了名字
Oh, yeah, we got first names.
阿特・金伯格  退役海军陆战队队员
Art Zimburger, late of the U.S. Marines,
我的好朋友
great friend of mine.
保罗・坎普先生  纽约时报记者
This is Mr. Paul Kemp, New York Times.
你就是那个作者
Oh, you're the writer.
-保罗是个小说家  -是嘛
- Paul's a novelist. - Uh-huh.
怎么成纽约时报了
New York Times?
对他来说都不认得
He don't know one from the other.
别纠结这个了  这个人是重点
Just go with it. This guy's key.
什么重点
Key to what?
我们讨论的重点
Key to the discussion we're about to have.
看看那些土著
Look at those mothers.
跟我来  坎普
Come with me, Kemp.
这是私人海滩
This is a private beach.
我们没踏上海滩
We are not on it.
你们是没有  但是我们在
No, but we are!
我们的行动是隐私
And what we do is private!
马上给我滚
Now get the fuck gone!
滚出这里
Get the fuck out of here!
再让我看到你
I see your face again,
一枪崩了你们
you're gonna have a 12-gauge shotgun telling you what to do.
说到撒旦
Talking about Satan...
苏联就是个满是撒旦的王国
if there ever was a kingdom of Satan, the Soviet Union is it.
对付共产主义的唯一方法就是毁了它
The only way to come to terms with Communism is to destroy it.
在它用民主浪潮打倒我们前打倒它
Hit it before it hits us in a devastating democratic strike.
别给少校倒了
No more for the major.
需要有人来振臂一呼
They're looking for a man to push that button,
我就是那个人
I am that man.
是的  就是你  亲爱的
Yes, you are, honey.
你真迷人  香诺
You look ravishing, Chenault.
谢谢
Thank you.
我来解救你啦
You need rescuing?
别带走他
Oh, don't take him away.
他很有趣
He's very entertaining.
我们刚在讨论古巴  还有  我不知道
We were discussing Cuba and, I don't know,
我们跑题了吧
we kind of veered off, didn't we?
保罗提出了一些自由派的观点
Paul presents us with a somewhat liberal point of view.
根本不存在自由主义者
There is no such thing as a liberal.
自由主义者就是
A liberal is a Commie with
念过大学  满脑子黑人思想的共产党员
a college education thinking Negro thoughts.
举个例子
Well, here's a fact for you.
76.4%的黑鬼是被莫斯科控制的
76.4% of all Negroes are controlled from Moscow.
这就是为什么卡斯特罗能一帆风顺
That's why Castro gets such an easy ride.
依我看  我们应该把古巴炸离地球
In my view, we ought to bomb Cuba off the face of the Earth,
-让那的人民都安生  -阿特
- let its people live in peace. - Art.
来吧  吃点东西
Hey. Come on, let's eat.
来吧
Come on.
荫凉地里那个人是谁
Who's the guy in the shades?
赛古拉的爸爸
Segurra's Daddy.
就是你要见的人
It's who you're waiting for.
谢谢你送我玫瑰
Thank you for my roses.
我还以为你没看到
I didn't think you noticed.
我当然看到了
Of course I noticed.
保罗  来认识一下
Paul, would you mind joining us?
你好  先生
How do you do, sir?
-坎普先生  -见到你很高兴
- Mr. Kemp. - Nice to see you.
坎普先生
Mr. Kemp.
首先我想说
Let me just start by saying
这完全是一个非正式聚会
this is a purely informal meeting.
顺便说句  你不用担心罗特曼  好吗
And, incidentally, you don't worry about Lotterman, okay?
罗特曼
Lotterman?
罗特曼和纽约时报有什么关系
What the hell's Lotterman got to do with the New York Times?
坎普先生为很多报社撰稿
Mr. Kemp subs for a variety of newspapers.
偶尔写写新闻报道
Occasionally, he writes for the news.
他业余时间做的事才是他的本职
What he does in his spare time is his affair.
我喜欢这样
That's how I like it.
我们想请你帮我们写点东西
We'd like you to do some writing for us.
这我知道
So I gather.
写什么
About what?
简而言之  我们想做一些事情
In a sentence, we want to set something up,
让大众成为我们的朋友
and have the public as our friends.
我们有很多种方法能办到
And there are a variety of ways we can do that.
我来告诉你
Let me tell you how this kind
怎么做  保罗
of thing works, Paul.
举个例子
Suppose, by way of example,
假如你想把税收提高五个百分点
you wanted to put up taxes by five percent.
最明智的办法是
The smart way of doing it
先提议涨十个百分点
is to float the idea of a ten percent hike.
让他们咆哮  焦躁不安
Let them all shout about it, get themselves in a fuss,
然后再给予适当的让步
then you offer concessions.
涨七个百分点怎么样  没门  他们说
"How about seven percent?" "No way," They'll say.
好吧  别伤感情  折中一下五个百分点
"All right, let's stay friends and make a compromise at five."
赢啦
Bingo.
他们觉得他们得到了点好处
They think they won something,
你得到了你预先希望的五个百分点
you get the five percent you wanted in the first place.
房地产也是一样的道理
Same thing applies to real estate.
你想建五幢房子
You want to build five houses,
先提交五十幢的规划申请
you put in a planning application for 50.
你想建几幢
How many do you want to build?
零
None.
我们要建一家酒店
We want to build one hotel.
这全是酒店
Well, looking around this place,
好像没人在意吧
I don't think anyone would notice.
不在这建
It isn't in this place.
是在一个岛上
It's an island.
由于一些敏感原因  现在还不想着手
Sensitive for a variety of reasons we don't want to get into now.
没人希望度假天堂变得满地旅馆
Nobody wants a paradise choked with hotels, but
但是大家最后会妥协  接受一家旅馆
everybody will be pleased to compromise at one.
这就需要将一些关键性文章
This is going to require some clever writing
放在关键性的位置
in various carefully placed articles.
这种做法合法吗
Isn't that kind of thing illegal?
要我说  坎普先生
If I may say, Mr. Kemp,
这个说法可不太合适
that's an inappropriate comment.
岛在哪里
Where's the island?
不能告诉你
Can't tell you.
暂时不行
Not yet.
小心驶得万年船  坎普先生
Discretion is paramount, Mr. Kemp.
如果你想要加入我们  你得签一些文件
If you want to join us, you'll have to sign some papers.
我们明天在豪尔的办公室开会
We're having a meeting tomorrow in Hal's office.
如果你想加入
If you want to be part of what will be
这项激动人心的工程  来吧
a very exciting project, come along.
有个人开着一辆滑稽的小车来找保罗
There's a man outside in a funny little car for Paul.
先生们  失陪了
Gentlemen, if you'll excuse me.
我得先走了
I have to run.
不留下来吗
Can't stay?
我听说美人鱼会在月光下现身呢
I hear the mermaids come out in the moonlight.
我一见到她  就知道
From the moment we met, I knew
我们之间要发生点什么
there was going to be something between us.
他是她未婚妻
It's called her fiance.
老天  我无可救药地越来越爱她
God, I'm so hopelessly and progressively in love.
不要把欲望错当成爱
Do not confuse love with lust,
不要在酒醉的情况下做判断
nor drunkenness with judgment.
需要我的建议吗
You want my advice?
不  如果和她有关  我不需要建议
No. If it involves her, no, I don't.
离她远点
Stay away from her.
还有离桑德森远点
And stay away from Sanderson.
别自不量力
You're way out of depth.
我不支持桑德森和他那狗屁坑人的岛
I got no brief for Sanderson or his pissy rip-off island.
我只想尝尝那苹果花般的口红和她做爱
I just want some apple blossom lipstick and fucks.
绝对不可能
You are in total denial.
她在和别人做爱
She's fucking someone else.
-哦  -而且据我所知
- Oh! - And as I understand it,
她快要和他结婚了
about to be married to him.
啦啦啦啦啦啦
La-la-la-la-la-la!
你根本没戏
You won't even make an invite.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
又回到刚开始的地方了
We're right back where we started.
卡布隆斯咖啡馆  营业至午夜
我们十分钟前路过
That is the same Cabrones we passed
卡布隆斯了
ten minutes ago.
我们需要人指路
We need directions.
进去找点吃的吧
Let's get in there and get something to eat.
别
No.
求你了  别
Please, no.
我可没一整天待在沙滩上
I haven't spent all day on a beach
和罪犯一起大嚼龙虾
munching lobster with criminals,
我饿死了
and I'm starving.
两瓶啤酒  两瓶朗姆酒  一份牛排
Two beers, two rums, one steak.
厨房下班了
The kitchen is closed.
好吧  那就两瓶啤酒  两瓶朗姆酒
All right then, two beers and two rums.
还有一份牛排
And one steak.
关门了  先生
Cerrado, Mister...
那不是我的问题
Yeah, but let's not bother me with that.
你们挂个牌子  上面说
You got a sign down there saying,
营业至午夜  那我就要点牛排
"Food til midnight," And I want a steak.
夹在中间的姑娘
Girl of the swamp.
这提醒我了  我们得要一份地图
Which reminds me, we need a map.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I think?
我在想我们朗姆酒喝多了
I think we're drinking too much rum.
没别的办法
There's no other way.
我眼前是两个烟灰缸和两个盐罐子
I'm getting double ashtray and double salt pot.
你也有莫伯格的神眼了
You got a Moburg bifocal.
天哪  太可恶了
Christ, this is heinous.
看上去肯定像个酒鬼
Imagine what it must be like to be an alcoholic.
两美元
$2.
给钱  走人
You pay and you go.
我没看到牛排
I don't see a steak.
没有牛排
No steak.
你什么意思  没有牛排
What do you mean, no steak?
我想他的意思就是没有牛排
I think he means no steak.
厨房下班了
The kitchen is closed.
我没法给你上牛排
I got no way of serving you.
听着  你不想听我说我倒霉的一天
Listen, you don't want to hear about my bad day,
我也不想看你摆臭脸色
and I don't want no grave side out of you.
你没法做熟就把生牛排端上来  我生吃
If you can't cook it, bring it like it is. I'll eat it raw.
两美元  给钱  走人
Two dollars, you pay and go.
别惹我
Don't bother me.
赶紧给钱  不然我报警了
You pay now, or I call the cops.
你要是根本不想给我上牛排
If you have no intention of serving me steak,
就给我滚远点
why don't you do your best to fuck off.
我感觉气氛很诡异
it seems to me there's a bad vibe developing.
那边有一两个怪人看我们的眼神不对劲
There are one or two oddities giving us the eye.
别神经兮兮的
Don't get paranoid.
他在打电话
He's on the phone.
干嘛
For what?
在餐馆点东西吃也犯法啦
Ordering food in a restaurant?
希望他打到联邦调查局去
Let's hope he's through to the FBI.
警察局吗
Si, la policia?
怎么了
What's the matter?
你笑什么
What are you smiling at?
我没笑啊
I'm not smiling.
只是显得随和点
I'm maintaining a casual face.
有个人刚走进来
A man just walked in
肯定把我们往坏处想了
and has good reason for regarding us in a negative light.
-我们吗  -是我
- Us? - Me.
他刚看到我了
And he's just seen me.
他想找白人报仇
And he wants revenge on the white man.
你在讲什么鬼话
The fuck are you talking about?
脸上有条疤的那个人
How about the one with the dent?
那个人的眼神
The one with the eye?
正是
The very same.
我们是走还是跑
Do we walk or run?
走
Walk.
我去推车
I'll push the car.
我们走  希望他今天心情不错
Let's walk and hope he's happy.
美国佬
Hey, Yankee.
Yankee!
别让我看到车灯
Don't let me see headlights.
Please don't let me see headlights.
我看到车灯了
I just seen headlights.
踩油门
Put your foot down.
我踩的就是油门
Where exactly do you think I got it?
不能开快点吗
Can you go faster?
已经最快了
Going fast as I can.
老天
Jesus Christ, man.
我们要死了  我们要死了
We're gonna be killed! We're gonna be killed!
准备好跑路
Get ready to run.
朝相反方向跑
Run in opposite directions.
酒给我
Give me the brew!
把酒给我
Give me the fucking brew!
保罗
Paul!
运气不错  我刚看到莫伯格
Piece of luck. I just saw Moburg.
估计他也看到我们了
At least I think he saw us.
他们搞了个夜间法庭
They got some kind of night court going.
他说我们是畜生
He says we were animals
大耍酒疯  暴怒狂躁
on a rampage of drunken anarchy,
向他们的一个警察泼汽油
poured gasoline on one of his cops.
老天  我们完了
Oh, my God, we're doomed.
你们还有什么话好说
You have something to say?
是的  法官大人  我有话说
Yes, Your Honor, I do.
首先跟我靠在一起的这个  我根本没见过
Firstly, this guy handcuffed to me, I never seen in my life.
其次  我们需要翻译指控
And second, we'd like a translation of the charges.
你听到他们说什么了
You heard what they said?
无意冒犯  我听到的是西班牙语
With respect, I heard people speaking Spanish.
你觉得这个国家
What kind of language do
是说什么语的  先生
you think we speak in this country, Mister?
他和我们不是一起的
He's not with us.
警察带他去定罪
The cops attached him to get a conviction.
你是否没付钱就离开卡布隆斯咖啡馆了
Did you leave the Cafe Cabrones without paying?
你是否对警官纵火  有还是没有
Did you set fire to the police officer, yes or no?
不幸的是  法官大人  是他自己闯进火里的
Unfortunately, Your Honor, he got in the way of our flame.
没错
That's right.
我们不可能向他头上浇汽油还大笑
No way did we pour gasoline on his head and laugh as we did.
不是像他说的那样
it wasn't like he said.
像他说的那样
Like he said?
像你说的那样你不会说西班牙语
Like you say you don't speak Spanish.
坎普先生不会说西班牙语
Mr. Kemp doesn't speak Spanish.
那他有许多机会去学习了
Well, he will have plenty of opportunity to learn.
对你们的指控可不轻
The charges against you are grave.
拘捕判处一年监禁
Resisting arrest carries a tariff alone of one year in prison.
更不用说用致命性武器攻击了
Never mind assault with a deadly weapon.
我要把这个案子
I'm going to refer this case
提交高级法庭
to a higher court.
同时  还要拘留
Meanwhile, I remand you both
你们两个30天
in custody for 30 days.
容我插一句  法官大人
If I may, Your Honor.
有话请讲  桑德森先生
Go ahead, Mr. Sanderson.
谢谢  法官大人
Thank you, Your Honor.
打断诉讼非我本意
It isn't my purpose to interrupt proceedings,
但是若关系到关押两位先生
but if the intention is to remand these gentlemen,
我恭敬地请求短暂休庭
I would respectfully ask for a brief recess
允许我联系两人的律师
to allow me to contact their counsel.
律师是谁
Who is who?
阿弗雷多・奎因诺斯
Alfredo Quinones.
看来必须把他从床上叫起来
It would necessitate getting him out of bed, of course.
但是考虑到这两位绅士的重要性
But given the importance of these gentlemen to
还牵涉到多方利益
various interests,
我敢说他肯定很乐意
I'm sure that he would be as pleased as I
像我一样大半夜跑到这来
to come down here at 3:00 in the morning.
赎我们要多少钱
How much did we cost him?
每人1000美元
About $1,000 apiece.
感激不尽
I can't thank you enough.
别迟到
Don't be late.
他妈的
Mother of balls!
我们得去把车找回来
We got to rescue the car.
现在不行  以后再说
Not now. We'll do it later.
我要去开会
I've got a meeting.
没有以后了
We do not have later.
车在他们手上已经12小时了
They've already had it 12 hours.
我知道这群狗杂种能干出什么来
I know how these bastards work.
他们能在12分钟内把火车抢得只剩车轴
They can strip a train to axles in 12 minutes.
能剩滴油就不错了
We'll be lucky to find an oil spot.
还要多久
How long is this gonna take?
我怎么知道
How would I know?
我不能迟到
I can't be late.
我真不知道你干嘛要去
I don't know why you're going at all.
那个男人不是个好东西
That guy is bad company.
他是个控制欲很强的混蛋
He's a manipulative prick.
他把我们带出监狱了啊
He manipulated us out of jail, didn't he?
我们就都卖给他了
Now he fucking owns us.
我的舌头好像...
I got a tongue like...
像条毛巾
Like a towel.
想喝啤酒吗
Want a beer?
问我想喝啤酒吗
Do I want a beer?
不  我不想
No, I do not.
我再也不沾酒精了
I am never gonna touch alcohol again.
这是个什么玩意
What fresh hell is this?
前排座椅不见了
Front seat's gone.
报废了  是吧
That's a write-off. Isn't it?
我有个好主意
You know what, I've got a brilliant idea.
那是什么声音
What's that?
这根轴负重太大
There's too much weight on the axle.
试着向前移一点
Try and move forward a bit.
要迟到了
Ugh, gonna be late.
要迟到好几天了
I'm gonna be a week late.
你在干嘛  萨拉
What are you doing, Sala?
我突然意识到我挺喜欢你的
I suddenly realize how much I like you.
你问我在干嘛是什么意思
What do you mean, what am I doing?
车轴有毛病了
There's something wrong with the axle.
天哪  那是被我们点着的警察
Oh, my God, it's the cop we set on fire.
表现得正常点
Try and look normal.
右转  右转
Make a right! Make a right!
-什么右转  右边没路  -往右转就行
- What right? There is no right. - Any right!
他来了  保罗  请进
Oh, there he is. Paul, come in.
抱歉  有些意料之外的状况
Sorry. There were unexpected developments.
我得回家  重新过这一天
I had to go home and start the day again.
可不是  时间就是不够用
Tell me about it. Some days are two sizes too small.
恐怕有人要先走了
Well, I'm afraid some of us had to leave.
金伯格先生  你认识的
But, Mr. Zimburger you know.
这是第一国家海事银行的格林先生
And this is Mr. Green of First National Maritime Bank.
要咖啡吗
You want some coffee?
我想我们得继续  豪尔
I think we should move right along, Hal.
-我要走了  -好的
- I gotta go. - Sure.
请坐  保罗
Sit down, Paul.
坎普先生  你可能已经知道
As you may know, Mr. Kemp,
这块岛屿是美国政府所有
the island is owned by the U.S. Government.
目前有一部分用作海军的射击场
Part of it presently used as a target range by the Navy.
我们的内部人士说
We know from internal sources...
你管我叫内部人士吗
Is that what you're calling me?
政府准备以租赁的方式让渡
...that the government is preparing to relinquish the lease,
这块岛屿上占地32平方英里的
and this place wakes up as 32 square miles
壮丽的前无古人的房地产事业将被开启
of magnificent and untouched real estate.
睁大眼睛
Knock your eyes out.
加勒比没有比这再美的海滩了
No prettier beaches in the Caribbean.
一条美轮美奂的小径环抱着整个岛屿
Orientated around one hell of a beautiful marina.
不是只建一座宾馆吗
Thought it was one hotel.
先建一座
We start with one hotel.
这是敲门砖
It's a foot in the door.
一旦运作起来  市场就打开了
Once we're up and running, we're servants of a market.
-就像这吗  -是的
- Like here? - Like here.
你看上去很焦虑  坎普先生
You look worried, Mr. Kemp.
他没有焦虑
He's not worried.
保罗和我昨晚都不太好过
Paul and I shared a tricky little night.
-是吧  保罗  -是
- Right, Paul? - Oh.
我们俩一夜无眠
Neither of us got much sleep.
我得走了  伙计们
I gotta go, guys.
你们继续讨论吧
Well, we'll leave you gentlemen to it.
坎普先生在合同上签字了吗
Has Mr. Kemp signed the papers?
现在就签
Doing that right now.
这是什么... 我签的是什么
What... What am I actually signing?
只不过是份保密协议
Just a confidentiality agreement,
确保我们可以相互信赖
affirmation of trust.
这样我们就在一条船上了
Just so we're all sitting in the same Jacuzzi.
防止有人搞破坏  你明白我的意思吧
In case a turd floats up, if you know what I mean.
保罗  我们去那边
Come on, Paul, let's go over here.
给你
Here you go.
那是句术语  保罗
It's just a technicality, Paul.
意思是你保证不向任何人透露这个计划
Means you promise not to talk to anybody about the project.
头感觉怎么样
How's the head?
不舒服
Unpleasant.
再次感谢你交了保释金
Gotta thank you again for putting up the bail.
我没看错你
It's held on my cognizance.
我肯定很多人都不会那么做
And I think it more than likely to slip various minds.
这地方遍地黄金  保罗
This place is a sea of money, Paul.
钱多的难以想象
Unbelievable money.
几乎所有的大公司都把资金投放到海外
Practically every major corporation hides its cash offshore.
我不喝  谢谢
No, thanks.
这对我们来说是好事
And that is good news for us,
因为我们就是海外
because we are the shore.
流入波多黎各的每一块钱
Not one dollar that wings its way into Puerto Rico
都不用交税
pays a cent in tax.
-一点不用吗  -一点也不用
- Nothing? - Not penny one.
包括化工企业
That includes chemical companies,
石油公司  矿产公司
oil companies, mining companies.
离这不到二十英里的山里
There's $12 billion worth of copper in mountains
有价值一百二十亿美元的铜矿
less than 20 miles from here.
一百二十亿美元
A dozen billion dollars.
这还有像我这样怎样赚钱的人
And there's people like me who know how to get it out.
说实在的
So, putting it into context,
我可不想为了一千块
I don't envisage the breaking of bones
累断了骨头
to get at a thousand bucks.
你刚才不在
Because you weren't here,
我替你安排了和金伯格的行程
I agreed to an itinerary with Zimburger on your behalf.
早上出发  没问题吧
You'll be traveling down in the morning. Hope that's okay.
你需要什么吗  保罗
What do you need, Paul?
你觉得和金伯格
Well, just in the context of this Zimburger thing,
会有进展吗
do you think there's a possibility of an advance?
我本不想问
I don't like to ask,
但是一涉及到钱罗特曼就很不靠谱
but Lotterman's pretty erratic with the paycheck, you know.
需要弄辆车
Need to get a hold of a car.
你没车吗
You don't have a car?
没有拿得出手的
Nothing too reliable.
还有
Plus, sooner or later,
我早晚得找个好地方住
I'm gonna have to find a decent place to live.
我们可以帮你
Well, we can help you with that.
你回来的时候
When you get back,
争取给你找到间海景房
we'll sort you out something with a view.
卡罗尔  我们还有什么车
Carol, what do we have in the garage?
不  不  不  那辆不行
No, no, no, no, no, not that.
好的  那辆可以  好的  谢谢
Yeah, that's fine. Okay, thank you.
车准备好了  出门的时候她把钥匙给你
Got you a car. She'll give you the keys on the way out.
有五百吧
Feels like 500?
是的  谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
保罗
Oh, Paul...
你下午怎么安排
How's your afternoon?
还没定
A half-written horoscope.
能帮我个忙吗
Do me a favor, will you?
开车到海滩接下香诺
Drive out to the beach and pick up Chenault.
要六点前到楼下
I need her downstairs by 6:00.
好的
All right.
这件怎么样
So, this one?
还有
Or...
这件呢
This one?
为什么准备的  聚会吗
What are these for, a party?
狂欢节要穿的
It's for carnival.
他没和你提过吗
Didn't he say anything to you about it?
-没有  -你一定要来
- No. - Oh, you've got to come.
我们都在游艇上
We're all going down on the boat.
他没邀请我
He didn't invite me.
那不是他举办的狂欢节
Well, it isn't his carnival.
这件吧
Oh, this one.
我喜欢那件
Um... I like the other one.
不错
Yes.
我喜欢这车
Love this car.
他送你了吗
Did he give it to you?
但愿
I wish.
很快
Fast.
你想打赌吗
You want a little bet?
赌什么
A bet about what?
赌你先喊出来
That you scream before I do.
赌我先喊
That I scream before you do,
因为什么喊
in relation to what?
这车能开多快
Well, how fast does it go?
我不知道
I don't know.
就赌这个
That's the bet.
今天我已经撞坏一辆了
I already crashed one car today.
没关系  我在门厅等他  然后告诉他撞坏了
It's okay. I'll just go sit in the foyer and wait for him.
我赢了有什么好处
What do I get if I win?
你赢了就知道了
I'll let you know if you do.
走吧  我送你回去
Come on, I'll take you back.
天啊  他们怎么知道的?
Christ, where'd they get this?
我也不记得了
I don't remember.
我一直都在躲着罗特曼
I've been slightly avoiding Lotterman.
你应该为你的自由而感谢我
You have me to thank for your freedom.
谢啦
Thanks.
我很不安
I got a feeling of total anxiety
我的焦虑总的来说就为一件事
trying to put my anxieties together in a single, coherent lump.
我他妈的没车
I'm fucked without a car.
我给大家弄了辆车
I got us a car.
楼下那辆雪佛兰
It's the Chevy downstairs.
那是桑德森先生的
It belongs to Mr. Sanderson.
那又怎样?
So what?
我去把这些打出来
I gotta go type this up.
我不知道是怎么了
I don't know what's going on.
他疯了  十二个版面全被他否了
He's freaking out and we're down 12 pages.
你他妈赶紧走
You better frigging do it!
我要是在这再看到你那肮脏的狗脸
I see your filthy animal face in here again,
我就把你关起来
I'll have you locked up!
萨拉  你要滚到哪去
What part of the building are you creeping towards, Sala?
-暗房  -警察正在找你
- Darkroom. - Cops are looking for you.
-找我吗  -找你
- Looking for me? - Looking for you.
报纸上那个弱智不是你吗
And it ain't just your mug in the paper!
倒霉的一天
What a day.
糟糕的一周
What a week.
我告诉你  我要离开这
I tell you, I'm out of here.
一路向北  去墨西哥
One way to friggin' Mexico.
听着  我明天去旅行
Listen, I got a trip tomorrow.
去桑德森的小岛
Sanderson's island.
不  不  不  天啊
No, no, no. Oh, dear.
那可是美元啊
It's green money,
我正在琢磨顺道去参加狂欢节
and I'm thinking of cutting across for the carnival.
你知道他们在圣托马斯岛办狂欢节
You know they got that carnival in Saint Thomas.
我知道
I know.
那你为什么不和我一起去
Why don't you come with me?
正好避避警察
Give the cops a few days to forget.
嗯  好
Yeah. Fun.
我们的海军  十二英寸口径
Our guys. 12-inch Naval,
船在十四英里外
14 miles out.
这没人住吗
Nobody lives here?
没有长住居民
No one who's staying.
拉加
Lazar!
金伯格先生
Mr. Zimburger.
这是拉加先生
This is Mr. Lazar,
我们新来的景区设计师
our much put-upon site architect.
-你好  -你好
- How do you do. - Hello.
蒙克先生  你认识吧
Mr. Monk, I think you know.
我是格林先生的助手
I assist Mr. Green,
第一海事银行
First Maritime Bank.
这是纽约时报的坎普先生
This is Mr. Kemp from The New York Times.
你说你叫什么来着
What did you say your name was?
-鲍勃・萨拉  -对  萨拉
- Bob Sala. - Yeah, Sala.
来自美国旅游作家协会
From American Travel Writers Association.
坎普先生正在为我们设计旅游册子
Mr. Kemp is preparing our brochure.
但愿您在这
"Wish you were here."
冰箱里有啤酒  先生们
Beer in the cooler, gentlemen.
隔壁什么都有
I have everything next door.
这个和这个是酒店的主楼
This and this are the main hotels.
二十二层
22 floors.
可以说是海湾守护者
Guardians of the bay, so to speak.
为什么颜色不同
Why the different colors?
蓝色是给游客的  红色是给投资商的
Blue is for public dissemination, red is for the investors.
对  山间别墅  临海公寓
Yeah. Hill villas, ocean condos.
海岸
Marina.
容纳两千辆车的停车场
Parking for 2,000 cars.
可是没有路啊
There's no roads.
靠  拉加  你忘记修路了
Damn it, Lazar, you forgot the roads!
我们正在修
We're building them. We're building them.
我们去吃午饭
Let's have some lunch.
一万名服务员
10,000 waiters, maids,
女仆  信差  门童  文员
bellhops, janitors, clerks.
还有  伺候肥仔的妓女们
whores for the fat man.
真不敢相信他们玩真的了
Hard to believe they'd do it.
我和那个建筑师谈过了
I was talking to that architect kind of guy.
他去圣托马斯岛  你想搭车吗
He's going to Saint Thomas, if you want a ride.
什么时候
When?
我怎么知道什么时候
How do I know when?
这的事情结束的时候
When he's finished here.
你听过奥斯卡・王尔德的一句话吗
You know what Oscar Wilde said?
人们只知事物的价格  却不知其真正价值
"They know the price of everything, The value of nothing."
两杯朗姆酒
Two rums.
我还以为你戒了
I thought you'd given up.
禁不住诱惑
Finally beat my willpower.
走  我们去那边
Come on, let's go here.
朋友  干杯
Hey, my amigo!
萝西是个歌手
Rosie's a singer.
保罗
Paul!
豪尔在哪
Where's Hal?
-船上  -在船上吗
- Boat. - Boat?
帮我找我的女伴
Help me find my girlfriend.
嘿  你好吗
Hey! How are you?
注意脚下
Watch your step.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - All right.
-这边  -谢谢
- There we go. - Thank you.
看看你
Look at you.
太棒了  拿瓶香槟
Good. Grab some champagne.
嘿  船长
Hey, Captain.
你带萨拉去岛上了
Did you take Sala to the island?
保罗  你不该那么做
You shouldn't have done that, Paul.
我们签保密协议就是为了不让外人去
It's why we have a confidentiality agreement.
他不感兴趣
He isn't interested.
他那嘴跟美联社一样
He's got a mouth like an AP wire.
我不知道他在那都干了些什么
I just don't know what he was doing there.
我也他妈搞不懂他在这干什么
And I sure as shit don't know what he's doing here.
不加入我们吗
Not going glum on us, are you?
一个人静静
Just thoughts.
什么书
What's the book?
古舟子咏
The Rime of the Ancient Mariner.
在1797年
It was written in 1797
一个叫柯勒律治的瘾君子写的
by a junkie called Coleridge.
他写这本书时25岁
He wrote that when he was 25 years old.
十年了我整天带着打字机乱转
I've been dragging a typewriter around with me for 10.
什么也没写出来
I've written nothing.
你已经写了几本书
You've written some books.
不算
Nah.
那些书空洞无物
They had no voice.
我不知道该怎么写出自己的风格
I don't know how to write like me.
我讨厌那样
I resent that.
不  我必须说他很好
No, I really have to say he's all right.
我必须承认
I have to admit.
生意归生意
Fair is fair. Fair is fair.
谢谢下午对我的招待
Thank you for the afternoon.
没准在镇上还能见到你
Maybe we'll see you in town.
你要去哪
Where you going?
她的朋友们在乐队表演
Her friend's playing in a band.
我们去看看
We're gonna go check it out.
我们也想去
Oh, we want to come.
我替她说明白了
I'll rephrase that.
是不想去
We don't want to come.
我们想去  女孩子们想去跳舞
Yes, we do. Us girls want to dance.
你明天要跳舞的
You're dancing tomorrow.
如果一切都是提前计划好的
What's the point of going to carnival
那来狂欢节还有什么意思
if everything is preplanned?
我要去跳舞
I want to dance,
如果你不陪我去  我和他们走了
and if you're not going to take me, i'm gonna go with them.
她把你镇住了  豪尔
She's got you trumped, Hal.
坐下  你醉了
Sit down. You're drunk.
那又怎样  大家都醉了
So what? So is everyone else.
走啦
Come on.
走吧  我们去跳舞  说不定很好玩
Come on, let's do it. It might be amusing.
小心  小心
Oh, cuidado. Careful.
到了  下车
Here we go.
我们玩够了  我们要走了
We're done.we are spent.
你们要走了
You're gonna go?
是啊  我们要走了
Yes, we're gonna leave.
你玩够了吗
You're done?
我真的不能再跳了
I can't dance no more. Really.
等等  我马上就出去
Hold on. You know what? I'll be out.
我去找一下香诺
Let me just get Chenault.
你想要朗姆还是啤酒
You want rum or beer?
嗯  都要
Um... Both.
两杯朗姆  两杯啤酒
Dos, uh, rum, uh, dos cervezas.
我们要走了
We're gonna go.
什么
What?
娜塔莉走了
Natalie's leaving,
我们也得走
So let's go.
-走吧  走  -不  不  不
- Come on, come on. - No, no, no, no.
香诺  过来  我们得走了
Chenault, come here. We're leaving.
-香诺  -不要
- Chenault. - Stop it!
香诺
Chenault!
嘿  怎么
Hey, what?
我听到你了*
I hear you
我听见你们了*
你们还好吗*
You all right?
来试试吧*
Try it
再试试*
Try it again
你再试试*
You try it again
再试试*
Try it again
我们坐下吧*
Shall we just sit?
再试一次*
Try again
像个婴儿*
Like a baby
难道你不试试吗*
Won't you try it?
你或许会喜欢*
You might like it
宝贝*
Honey
没关系的*
it's all right
我试过*
I tried
很好*
That's right
香诺  过来  香诺
Chenault, come here! Chenault!
把你们的手拿开  你们这些混蛋
Get your hands off me, you motherfucker!
你们敢惹我
You want to fuck with me?
知道我是谁吗
You know who I am?
你们这帮混蛋
You motherfucker!
知道我是谁吗
You know who I am?
你找死吧  快走  快走
You're a dead man! Go! Go!
把手拿开
Get your hands off me.
你找死  滚
You're a dead man! Go!
没事
Forget it.
我给你叫辆出租车  滚开
We'll call you a cab. Fuck off!
我得把那女孩带走
I gotta get the girl.
她正玩得高兴呢  我们打烊了
She's having a good time. We closed.
你聋了
You deaf?
我说我们打烊了
I said we closed.
不行  保罗
No way, Paul.
行不通
No way.
我四处都找过了
I looked everywhere.
我去了宪兵队
I went to the gendarme.
怎么样
And?
我们又回去了
We went up there.
什么都没有  没人
Nothing. Nobody there.
只有一个老太太在擦地
But an old woman with a mop.
她比警察都有用
She was more help than the cops were.
他说你女朋友喜欢别人我有什么办法
"What can I do if your girlfriend likes someone else?" He said.
保罗  他说得对
He's right about that, Paul.
她不是你女朋友
She's not your girlfriend.
没准  没准她已经回船上了
Maybe... Maybe she went back to the boat.
你  你去船上找过了吗
Did you... Did you try the boat?
没有
No.
我觉得他不会让她回去的
I don't think he'd let her back on.
她和你在一起吗
Is she with you?
你他妈管好你自己的事情
Why don't you mind your own goddamn business?
钥匙给我
I want the keys.
雪佛兰
The Chevy.
坎普  是你搞砸的
You blew it, Kemp.
都生锈了
It's all rust.
拖船上的救生圈都比这轮胎强
I've seen better tires hanging over the side of a tug.
要还是不要啊
You want it or not?
好  我们要
Yeah, we want it.
大家周五都去拿钱  是吗
Everyone turns up for their Friday check, right?
没钱  也就不会有罗特曼
No check, no Lotterman.
所以我去找他那位丑得惨不忍睹的老婆
So I go around to see that unforgivably ugly wife of his.
她告诉我他去迈阿密了
She tells me he's gone to Miami.
干什么
For what?
你不知道  我也不知道
You don't know, I don't know.
但是他的手下回来了
But the scabs are back.
自从梅瑞走后
Since Merell went,
报社领导一个不如一个
the paper took a turn for the worse.
有什么需要的吗
Is there anything in the spinner?
我们需要新的床单
We need a fresh sack.
我或许有别的东西会让你们感兴趣
Well, maybe I can interest you gentlemen in something else.
什么  死吗
Like what, death?
史上最强的毒品
Like the most powerful drug in the history of narcotics.
我还没权利讨论和公开这个
I'm not at liberty to discuss or disclose.
我只能说这东西太厉害了
All I can tell you is this stuff is so powerful,
他们把这东西给共党分子
they give it to Communists.
谁干的
Who does?
FBI
The FBI.
FBI为什么让共党分子爽翻呢
Why would the FBI get Communists high?
我也不知道
That I can't help you with.
用的时候就像滴眼药
You take it like eye drops.
弄到眼里
In the eye?
我认为是
So I understand.
能让眼睛看到某些东西
It makes the eye see things.
可以看到不一样的东西
You see a different reality.
你想用什么换
What do you want for it?
如果你帮我个忙
I'll throw it in with the bike
这就算你买车的赠品
if you do me a favor.
帮什么忙
What's the favor?
我想让你跟我一起去洗手间
I want you to come to the bathroom with me.
没问题
He's your man.
-五十美元  对吗  -是的
- $50, right? - Yeah.
他想让我看他的老二
He wants me to look at his dick.
我当然拒绝了
I flatly refused.
他让你看那个干吗
What does he want you to look at it for?
他说他那个出问题了
Says there's something wrong with it.
这是男人的问题
It's a gentleman's matter.
我才不看
I'm not looking at it!
好吧  把药还给我
All right, give me the drugs back.
不  等等
No! Wait.
我来看
I'll look at it.
我用镜子看
I'll view it in the mirror.
是淋病吗
Is it clap?
答对了
A standing ovation.
你看见什么了吗
You see anything?
没有
No.
我也没有
Neither do I.
我们再等五分钟
We'll give it another five minutes.
应付开支方面有问题吗
Trouble making ends meet?
那么你需要借贷人  对的
Then, you need the Lending Man. Right.
当你缺钱的时候
When money dries up fast,
欢迎您来我们这里获取现金
you're welcome to our cash.
来找借贷人借钱吧
So borrow from the Lending Man.
现在就给借贷人打电话吧
Call the Lending Man now.
我们用药多长时间了
How long since we took it?
不知道
I don't know.
有段时间了
A while.
他是胡说八道的  不是吗
Bullshit, isn't it?
是胡说吗
Is it bullshit?
天哪
Jesus.
你那舌头像臭肠子
Your tongue is like an accusatory giblet.
上帝啊  别伸过来
For Christ's sake, keep it out.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你那是撒旦的舌头
Your tongue belongs to Satan!
你是不是疯了
Are you out of your mind?
把它弄出去
Keep it out!
要是你再这样  我就杀了你
If it goes back into your mouth, it'll kill you.
我们必须把它弄进水池
We've got to get it into the sink!
你吓到我了
You're giving me fear.
住手  你吓到我了
Stop it! I've got fear!
去你妈的  我也是
Fuck you. So do I.
你爽翻了吧  白痴
You're high, you fool.
喝点朗姆酒吧
Drink some rum.
我刚才失控了吧
I thought I was losing grip in there.
我们用的是什么
What did we take?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们应该再弄点
We need to get some more.
怪不得
That explains it.
不是吗
Doesn't it?
怪不得什么
Explains what?
这个世界
The world.
还有我们
And us.
我很好奇你们如何
I wonder what it is
看待我们不同的世界
you might think about our different worlds.
他醉眼朦胧的看着我说
He looked at me kind of sideways and said,
人类是这个世界上唯一
"Human beings are the only creatures on earth
维护上帝的生物
"that claim a God.
也是唯一行为不受上帝约束的生物
"And the only living thing that behaves like it hasn't got one.
这世界只属于你吗
"Does the world belong to no one but you?"
他说这话的时候  我大吃一惊
And when he said it, I was taken aback.
并不是因为是他说的这话
Not because of who was doing the talking,
而是因为我最终明白了
because I finally understood the connection
吃不上饭的孩子
between children scavenging for food
和银行的闪亮门牌之间的关系
and shiny brass plates on the front doors of banks.
我们得走了
Gotta go.
进来
Shh. Come in.
Come in.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
等我一下
Give me a minute.
我在楼下等你
I'll be waiting for you downstairs.
你能过来真不错
Oh, how nice of you to drop in.
我去了狂欢节
I was covering the carnival.
我可不是这么听说的
That's not what I heard.
我听说你沐浴在桑德森的月光里
I heard you were in the moonlight for Sanderson.
我什么
I was what?
沐浴桑德森的月光
Moonlighting for Sanderson.
赛古拉在哪里
Where's Segurra?
赛古拉已经不在了
Mr. Segurra's no longer with us.
我给你写了一篇故事
I got a story for you.
是啊  你可能注意到了我很忙
Yeah, you may have noticed that I'm somewhat busy.
这个真的很重要  牵扯到
This is real important, involving Mr.
赛古拉先生和桑德森先生
Segurra and Mr. Hal Sanderson.
我来告诉你为什么不重要
I'm gonna tell you how important it isn't.
我有21个等我发钱的职员
I got 21 jobs on the line
还有一家要倒闭的报社
and a newspaper going under.
把这个印出来  你就能卖掉了
Print this, and you'll sell it.
一场精心设计的骗局
A planning scam.
真的是对天堂的掠夺
Literally despoliation of a paradise.
数千人将会像垃圾一样被扫进大海
A thousand people will be swept into the sea like garbage.
你真古怪  坎普
You are weird, Kemp.
关键不是对他们有什么影响  是对你
It's not what it's doing to them, it's what it's doing to you.
这叫做新闻
It's called journalism.
真好笑
Oh, make me laugh.
我以前让你少喝
I asked you to tidy up the booze,
你连屋子里的酒都不肯拿走
you couldn't even sweep out a room.
你觉得你为什么能在这工作
Why do you think you're working here?
因为你身上没有一点适合做记者
'Cause you're everything that's wrong with a journalist.
而你身上每一点
And you're everything
都是对报纸的侮辱
that's wrong with this insult of a newspaper.
完全同意
Unanimously agreed.
你他妈闭嘴  莫伯格
Why don't you shut it, Moburg?
你简直就是浪费了人类的精子
You are a waste of human sperm.
你慢慢的痛苦的去死吧
Die a prolonged and relentlessly agonizing death!
她是你的了
Enjoy her.
我给你泡了茶
Made you some tea.
你应该试着睡一觉
You should try and sleep.
我占用了你的床
I stole your bed.
没事
It's okay.
我去写东西
I'm going to write.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
别这么说
Don't be sorry.
你帮了我一个大大的忙
You did me the best favor I ever had.
这不是做梦  香诺
There is no dream, Chenault.
只不过是可耻的贪婪
Just a piss puddle of greed,
在世上蔓延开来
spreading throughout the world.
我想对你们读者做出承诺
I want to make a promise to you, the reader.
我不知道明天能不能做到
And I don't know if I can fulfill it tomorrow
连后天能不能也不知道
or even the day after that.
但是我报道了这个世上的混蛋们
But I put the bastards of this world on notice.
我不关心他们的利益
That I do not have their best interests at heart.
我要替我的读者说话
I will try and speak for my reader.
这就是我的承诺
That is my promise.
这是墨水与勇气共鸣的声音
And it will be a voice made of ink and rage.
坐下吧  我给你煮了咖啡
Sit down. I made you coffee.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
一份你的  一份我的
One for you and one for me.
天哪  怎么一起来就看到这个
Oh, man, I would rather not start the day with this.
-这是什么  -传票
- What is it? - It's a writ.
意味着我们要上法庭了
Means we're going to court.
这意味着只要他们愿意就可以拘捕我们
It means they can arrest us, should they so desire,
什么时候都行
any damn minute they please.
我们得去找个律师谈谈
We need to speak to a lawyer.
我们连电话都没有
We don't even have a phone.
我认识一个老家伙  是个西班牙律师
I know an old guy, Spanish Advocate.
他欠我个人情
Kind of owes me one.
你去把衣服穿好  我们去找他
You should get dressed. We'll go down there.
没水了  我身上还有肥皂
Water ran out. I'm covered in soap.
操  我去看看吧
Fuck it. See what I can do.
这是怎么回事
What's it for?
是豪尔
Uh... it's Hal.
原来我们签合同了  现在他不干了
He put up a bond for us on this thing, and now he's pulled it.
你看
Here.
他是个骗子  保罗
You know he's a crook, Paul.
法院传的是我们
And we get the writs.
这是什么
What is it?
是希特勒
It's, er... Hitler.
完了
It's over.
什么完了
What is?
他们把报社关了
They shut us down.
他就站在那里对我们撒谎
He just stood there and lied to us.
他还不如一台破旧收银机
He hasn't got the morality
有职业道德
of a clapped out cash register.
我很不想跟你们这么说  伙计们
I hate to tell you this, guys,
但是没有遣散费
but it was to avoid severance.
我们都知道会这样  查理
We all know what it was for, Charlie.
-我们能做什么  -什么都不做
- What are we gonna do? - Nothing.
我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do,
除了去劳动局告他
except report him to the labor board,
这跟什么都不做一样
which is the same thing as doing nothing.
我不同意
I disagree.
我们得反击
We gotta strike back
要让这混蛋倒在自家门前
and nail this bastard to his own front door.
那感谢上帝  我们要怎么做呢
And how, pray, do we do that?
我们印刷报纸
By printing the paper.
我们手上罗特曼的把柄多了
We got tons of stuff on Lotterman.
他玩过的所有小伎俩
Every happy maggot with his hand in the till.
这很有可能是最后一次发行了
It may be the last-ever issue,
但是我们用满腔怒火来发行
but we go out in a blaze of rage.
你在说什么  发一次要花两千两百美元
What are you talking about? It costs $2,200 a shot.
我们去找工贼
We bring in the scabs.
收钱帮人偷盗的游民
他们为了钱什么都干
They're picketing for money.
你这是在幻想
You're through the looking glass.
我们连买酒的钱都不够
We haven't even got enough money for drinks.
这根本不值得斗
It's not worth the fight.
这已经出现很久了
This has been coming down the pike for a long time.
该结束的时候自然就结束了
You got to know it's over when it's over.
这份破报纸
This lousy little Caribbean rag is nothing
别人都拿来包鱼头
but a wrapping for fish heads.
再说  已经停工了
Plus, it's a lockout.
去他妈的停工
Fuck the locks.
我们直接闯进去
I say we just walk in.
有人和我一起吗
Anybody with me?
鲍勃
Bob?
你知道我是支持你的
You know I'm with you.
我们没付钱
We didn't pay the bill.
香诺在哪里
Where's Chenault?
她去纽约了
She's gone to New York.
她给我留了一百美元
She left me $100.
真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
她一分钱都没有
She didn't have any money.
你应该拿这钱去找她
You should use it to go with her.
坐红眼航班  五十块就够了
Red-eye for 50 bucks.
不
No.
我哪里都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
不管怎样  我都要把报纸发行出来
By some means or another, I'm gonna put the paper out.
把这个混蛋的事印刷出来  然后再走
Print the bastard, then we're gone.
面对现实吧  保罗
Face the reality, Paul.
没工作  没钱  没女人
There's no job, no money, no girl,
还有拘捕我们的传票
and a warrant out for our arrest.
这已经没什么可争的了
There's no contest.
多诺万是对的  这不值得斗争
Donovan's right, it ain't worth the fight.
我不是多诺万
I'm not Donovan!
我跟别人也不一样
And I'm not like the others.
我现在告诉你  下次再有油嘴滑舌的笨蛋
I'm telling you right now, next time some greasy moron
跟我废话  我饶不了他
starts bullshitting me, I'm going after him.
就算到了美国总统那里也一样
All the way up to the president of the United States.
我只是想赢一次
I just want to win one once.
就一张纸
One sheet.
一百美元你什么也干不了
You ain't gonna get far on $100.
有些工贼不收钱
Some of the scabs will do it for nothing.
我们需要二十个人  还有小货车
We're gonna need 20 guys, plus vans.
不  不  你只需要两千美金
No, no, all you need is two grand.
我们的朗姆酒喝完了
We're out of rum.
感觉像是上帝  突然觉得恶心
It's as if God, in a fit of disgust,
就决定把我们都消灭了
has decided to wipe us all out.
公鸡打了三次鸣了
Yeah, the cock crows thrice.
怪兽怎么样
What about El Monstruo?
我一百美元押怪兽赢
Bet the $100 on El Monstruo.
你怎么知道他住这里
How do you know he lives here?
我见过他出来
I saw him come out.
最好让我一个人去
You better let me do this on my own.
要是他拿到了  我们应该拿到内博老爹那里去
If he gets it, we should bring it to Papa Nebo.
那是谁
Who's that?
我的巫医
My witch doctor.
她是个两性人
She's a hermaphrodite.
就是这里  就是这里
Stop here! Stop here!
白天她开垃圾车
By day, she drives a garbage truck.
晚上她就是内博老爹
By night, she becomes Papa Nebo,
死灵的两性神使
the hermaphroditic oracle of the dead.
当墓地守护者萨穆迪老爹
When permission is granted from Papa Samedi,
同意了
the keeper of the cemetery,
她就去拜访
she'll visit,
她挖出一具尸体
and she'll dig up a corpse.
地下尸体身上的器官
Certain organs of the disgrounded stiffs
在巫术里必不可少
are indispensable for use in ouangas.
这是胡说的  对吗
This is horseshit, isn't it?
他治好了我的老二
She cured my prick.
她想知道你想要什么
She wants to know what you want.
我们想让她赋予这只鸡能力
We want her to empower this fowl.
我们希望它得到祝福
We want it blessed
任何跟它打斗的都要死
and anything that tries to fight it, dead.
把鸡拿过来
Bring forth the fowl.
她说  这世上没有任何鸡
She says that no fowl on Earth
能够挑战它
could challenge this cockerel and survive.
很好
Great.
她下诅咒怎么样
How's she off for curses?
很好
Pretty good.
那我们诅咒一下桑德森  让他硬不起来
Let's have a curse on Sanderson. Make his dick fall off.
还有那个银行的混球  格林
And that fucker at the bank, Green.
格林先生
Mr. Green.
天哪
Jesus!
诅咒启动了
Curse active!
好  来吧
Okay, come on.
打败一只了  还有两只
One down, two to go.
好  我去给莫伯格打电话
Okay. I'm gonna call Moburg.
好吧
Okay.
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
他不在
He isn't there.
他必须在
He has to be.
他不在
He isn't there.
-你去哪里了  -抱歉
- Where have you been? - Sorry.
我没听见电话
I never heard the phone.
怎么样了
How's it going?
赢了  伙计  我们赢了
Winning, man. We're winning.
所有人都到了吗  所有人都到了吗
Is everyone there? Is everyone there?
是的  都到了
Yeah, everyone's here.
货车呢
What about the vans?
货车呢  莫伯格
What about the vans, Moburg?
对的  对的  货车
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, vans.
你听见了吗
You hear that?
我们马上过去
We're on our way.
发生什么事了
What the hell is going on?
他说了人都到了
He said he had the men.
《圣胡安星报》停业
禁止擅入
所有关于前业主的起诉都将...
"All claims against the former owners will be..."
由迈阿密第一海事银行签署
"Signed on behalf of First Maritime Bank, Miami."
桑德森的朋友  格林先生
Sanderson's pal, Mr. Green.
抱歉  保罗
Sorry, Paul.
我不知道怎么说
I didn't know how to say.
他们  他们把所有的机器都拿走了
They... they took all the machines out.
不是所有的东西
Not everything,
但是重要的都搬走了
but just the parts that matter.
我放你们进来
I'll let you in.
我就想要个头版
All I wanted was a front page.
也许这是好事
Probably for the best.
也许永远完不成了
Probably would've never pulled it off.
多少  你们赢了多少钱
How much... how much did you guys win?
不到六千
Just under six grand.
好吧  你们
Oh, yeah, well, you...
至少现在你们可以把违约金付了
At least you can pay off the bond now.
去他妈的违约
Screw the bond.
我们走吧
We're out of here.
结束了
It's over with.
半夜有一趟泛美航空的班机
There's a midnight Pan Am.
我可不会冒险去机场
I'm not risking the airport.
不
No.
这个岛欠我们一艘船
I figure this island owes us a boat.
我他妈要去桑德森那里牵一艘走
And I'm fuckin' taking one of Sanderson's.
你闻到了吗
You smell it?
这是混球的味道
It's the smell of bastards.
也是真相的味道
It's also the smell of truth.
我闻到了墨水的味道
I smell ink.
总是想起*
Always think
过去的日子*
about the days gone by.
我播种下的那些童年*
When the childhood I have sown
出现在天空中*
appears in the sky.
但是我不再是个简单的人*
But I'm not the simple man
当初那个男孩儿*
the boy I used to be.
不  我学会了想象生活*
No, I learned to picture life...
我得去把鸡拿回来
I got to take the hen back.
我发现*
And I found
寻寻觅觅之后*
after all the searching,
生命才是我的骄傲所在*
life was only what I made it.
寻觅过所有新鲜的玩乐*
After all the searching for new games to play...
一路顺风多挣钱
Find yourself a trade wind.
寻寻觅觅之后*
After all the searching,
生命才是我的骄傲所在*
life was only what I made it
寻觅过所有新鲜的玩乐*
After all the searching for a new game to play.
过自己的生活*
Live my life away.
曾见过巨龙撼动墙壁*
Saw a dragon shake the theater walls.
而尖塔的钟声*
While the steeple bell
痛苦的悲鸣*
rang out in anguished calls.
我见到*
And I turn my eyes
头上有鸟飞过*
to see a bird fly overhead.
我梦想着自己能拥有*
And I dreamt its wings of freedom
它的自由之翼*
could be mine instead.
这是旧旅途的结束  也是新旅途的开始
我发现*
And I found
梦想过后*
after all the dreaming,
坎普回到了纽约  和香诺结了婚  成为了美国最受人尊敬的记者
他写出了自己的想法  即使你是他笔下的"混蛋"之一  他也是一位可敬的敌人
生命才是我的骄傲所在*
life was only what I made it.
在梦想过*
After all the dreaming
新鲜的玩乐之后*
of new games to play.
一醉方休*
I drink my life away.
纪念亨特・S・汤普森  1937-2005
我爱你们*
Love you all.
活下去*
And livin' on.
Livin' life the way.
你还记得我吗*
Do you remember me?
时间在波浪中停留*
The ocean rolled time was slow.
我们感受活力*
We felt an energy.
公鸡在打鸣*
The cock was crowing.
莱姆酒在流淌*
The rum was flowing.
美人鱼烧毁*
A mermaid burns to see.
飞跃海洋*
Beyond the sea.
我在眺望  在眺望*
I long to see, I long to see
是否有我的一页*
if there's a page for me.
我的一页*
A page for me.
在你的日记中*
In your diary.